[music]
>> Hello everyone and welcome to a new
episode of What's Cooking.
For today, I'm going to show you a new
feature that is coming up with the next
release.
And it's for those of you who use
analysis mode to perform data analysis.
So, with this new
feature, you will now be able to export
those analysis tabs that you have
defined from web client
and deliver them with your own AL
extensions.
This [clears throat] makes it easier to
persist these analysis tabs and also
share them with other users and other
environments.
This will also allow us to create our
own predefined analysis views based on
some of the most common scenarios and
deliver them with our base application.
So, to show you how it works, I'm just
going to go ahead and jump into analysis
mode for my sales order list.
And here you can see that I have already
created a
a new analysis view um where I have
added a related column to bring the
country and region code for the the
customer.
And then I also have grouped my my sales
order based on this country or region
code.
You can also use create analysis
compiler assist to create a new analysis
um with with AI.
But in this case, before I export my
analysis view, I'm going to add a
description for it.
This is also something that we have
added with this release. So, now I can
just go on and rename and add a
a description for this analysis view
that will give some context or help uh
users see how they can use this tab.
No.
>> So, in this case, I have I got the
description.
I when I hover over it, I will be able
to see that one.
So, now my analysis view is ready to be
exported. So, I can go into share and
export definition.
And here I will just get my analysis tab
in the shape of a JSON file.
And here I have all the information to
recreate tab. So, I have the title, the
tooltip, target page, and other filters,
grouping, or related columns that I have
added to my to my tab.
So, the first thing that I need to do is
get that
file into my
um into my extension.
And then in this case, I'm just going to
add this view to the sales order list.
So, I need to create a page extension
and use this new syntax that is also
coming up with this release
uh for analysis views.
So, it's quite similar to other
controls. The only difference here is
that I have the definition file
property.
And this property should point to the
path to my JSON file
uh that I have just downloaded that
contains the definition for my analysis
view.
In a similar mode, I can also set
properties for the caption or the
tooltip, which will override the name
and the description.
Or I can also uh set the visibility from
AL code directly.
In a similar way, I can also create a
page customization
and then assign this customization to a
profile or profile extension.
And in this case, I'm just making sure
that this new tab is only visible for
the those users that have a order
processor profile.
So, this way I can also create different
analysis tabs that are tailored for
different users and assign them to to
these different profiles.
And in a similar way, if I'm also
defining new pages or list pages,
um I will also be able to have this new
section to define analysis views that
are available with this list page.
So, that was it for how to add analysis
views in a year.
That was very straightforward, so let's
get this extension published in another
different environment.
And that is my sales order list, and if
I go into analysis mode,
then I will be able to see this new
analysis view
um that comes from that extension.
You will notice that this analysis view
is a bit different from the others.
First of all, because it contains a
um
a lock icon, which will indicate that it
comes from the extension, and also
indicate that this analysis view is not
editable.
So, I cannot really do some more
filtering or sorting or grouping or
anything like that
um on this on this analysis view.
But, if I do want to create do more
advanced data analysis on top of this
file, then I can just go ahead and
duplicate it.
And this is now my tab, and now I can
just have all my filtering and pivoting
back, so I can just perform more data
analysis on top of that view.
Another thing to to take into
consideration is that maybe users, or me
in this case, maybe I don't really want
all the analysis tabs that come with the
AL extensions. So, if I don't really
find one relevant, then I can just go
into the menu and choose to hide it.
And now this will hide the the analysis
view just for me.
If I made a mistake or I want to bring
it back, then I can always go into
personalization mode, like we do with
other controls, such as views.
Um and I will find my my hidden analysis
views uh grayed out, and then I can go
into the menu
and just uh click on show.
And as you can see, this will bring my
analysis view back and I can see it back
again.
So, that was it for the new addition uh
for analysis mode, and hopefully you
will also like it very much.
Um yeah, and that was it. Thank you
everyone for listening in.